Finding Aid for the Raymond Chandler Papers, 1930-1959
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence Between Raymond Chandler and James Sandoe
    - James Sandoe to Raymond Chandler. Boulder., 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12-17)
      - February 23/24, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Date has been penciled in on both pages.
      - March 14, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - May 15, 1951., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - October 8, 1951., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - December 30/31, 1951., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - March 30/31, 1952., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - July 16/17, 1952., (1 leaf [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - March 18/19, 1954., (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - [Miscellaneous]
    - Raymond Chandler to Hamish Hamilton. La Jolla., June 11, 1947; (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon, signed). (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Chandler has penciled “Sandoe” on this carbon.
    - Gordon R. Williams, Brentano's, to Raymond Chandler. Los Angeles., December 21, 1948; (1 leaf [1p.], typescript signed). (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Personal: Professional Organizations
  - Mystery Writers Association - Manuscript. La Jolla., 1959; (3 items: 10pp. - typescript with holograph corrections, newsletter, photocopy). (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Speech for Mystery Writers Association Meeting in New York. RC's speech typed on blue index cards.
    With copy of The Third Degree, Mystery Writers Association newsletter for February 1959, and photocopy of Raymond Chandler's speech.
    Gift of Mrs. Helga Greene, May 1959.
- Writings By Raymond Chandler
  - Unpublished
    - The Trench Raid - Manuscript. n.p., n.d.; (1 leaf, typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Apparently unpublished fragment about World War I.
  - Published
    - Manuscripts. n.p., 1911-1959 (Box 4-9)
      - The King. n.p., circa (1911); (1 leaf, typescript). (Box 2, Folder 34)
        With note in red ink, “Published, probably around 1911, in either The Academy (England) or The Westminster Gazette.”
      - Studies in Extinction. La Jolla., circa 1948; (4 leaves, typescript carbon). (Box 4, Folder 8)
        Review of Murder Plain and Fanciful by James Sandoe. Murder Plain and Fanciful was published by Sheridan House, New York 1948.
      - The Little Sister. n.p., n.d.; (280 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections). (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Published by Houghton Mifflin, Boston, 1949.
      - Casual notes on the mystery novel. n.p., 1949; (5 leaves, typescript carbon). (Box 4, Folder 13)
        Published in The Writer (vol.76, no.7). Boston, July 1963.
      - A Couple of Writers. La Jolla., January 27, 1950; (31 leaves, typescript with numerous holograph corrections). (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - The Long Good-Bye. La Jolla., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
        First published by Houghton Mifflin, Boston, 1954.
        - pp.1-217 of 425., (Typescript with corrections). (Box 5, Folder 5)
          Folder 1 of 2.
        - pp.218-425 of 425., (Typescript with corrections). (Box 5, Folder 6)
          Folder 2 of 2.
      - Requiem. n.p., January 1955; (1 leaf). (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Author's proof.
        With Raymond Chandler's holograph note: “Perfect as far as I can see (the proof I mean, not the poem). Raymond Chandler.”
      - Crosstown With Neil Morgan., 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 9-14)
        “Crosstown” was a featured column in the San Diego Evening Tribune.
        Material in folders 9-14 relate to or are by Raymond Chandler.
        - “My San Diego.” San Diego., August 28, 1956; (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript). (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - Letter from Raymond Chandler to Neil Morgan expressing appreciation of his “Crosstown” column. La Jolla., August 30, 1956; (3 items: 1 leaf and 2 copies - photostatic copy and 2 carbon copies). (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - Guest column by Raymond Chandler. San Diego., March 1, 1957; (3 leaves, typescript). (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - “Reader's right” by Raymond Chandler. San Diego., June 4, 1957; (3 leaves, typescript). (Box 5, Folder 12)
          Raymond Chandler's rebuttal to an article by Rene MacColl in the London Daily Express.
        - Guest column by Raymond Chandler on love and marriage. San Diego., July 12, 1957; (2 leaves, typescript). (Box 5, Folder 13)
        - “Reader's right” by Raymond Chandler on Carmichael and Grunion. San Diego., March 8, 1958; (2 leaves, typescript). (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Playback., 1958 (Box 5-7)
        - Half-sheet original with enclosures. La Jolla., January 28, 1958; (pp.1-92 of 317 leaves - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 5, Folder 16)
          With 2pp. of points to check.
          Folder 1 of 3.
        - Half-sheet original. La Jolla., January 28, 1958; (pp.93-182 of 317 leaves - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 5, Folder 17)
          Folder 2 of 3.
        - Half-sheet original. La Jolla., January 28, 1958; (pp.183-317 of 317 leaves - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 5, Folder 18)
          Folder 3 of 3.
        - “Copy 1.” La Jolla., 1958; (224 leaves, typescript). (Box 6, Folder 1)
          Gift of Mrs. Helga Greene, July 1959.
        - “First version.” La Jolla., 1958; 2 items: 188 leaves, 2 leaves - typescript, typescript signed with holograph notes). (Box 6, Folder 2)
          With letter from Helga Greene re questions on plot and Chandler's answers.
        - “2nd version.” La Jolla., 1958; (197 leaves, typescript carbon). (Box 6, Folder 3)
          Another copy marked with “2nd copy” in Chandler's hand.
          Gift of Houghton Mifflin at the request of Raymond Chandler, December 1959.
        - no.3. La Jolla., 1958; (2 items, 197 leaves and 5pp. - typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 6, Folder 4)
          With 3pp. of emendations and revisions in Chandler's hand.
        - Typescript for American edition. La Jolla., 1958; 2 items: 197 leaves, 1 leaf - typescript carbon). (Box 6, Folder 5)
          With Raymond Chandler's note on wrapper: “Mr. Harris. Sorry my secretary forgot these. UCLA. Library wants the scripts when you are done with them. Regards. Raymond Chandler.”
          Carbon copy of “no.3” was made by the Helga Greene Literary Agency.
        - H.N. Swanson agency copy. San Diego., January 28, 1958; (pp.1-76 of 188, Ozalid [?] photostatic copy). (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - H.N. Swanson agency copy. San Diego., January 28, 1958; (pp.77 -135 of 188, Ozalid [?] photostatic copy). (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - H.N. Swanson agency copy. San Diego., January 28, 1958; (pp.136-188 of 188, Ozalid [?] photostatic copy). (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Book Review. London., 1958; (5 leaves, holograph). (Box 8, Folder 1)
        Dr. No by Ian Fleming. Published in the London Times.
        With page proofs and a typed transcription of the text.
      - The Pencil. La Jolla., October 25, 1958; (69 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Original cataloger's note: “First Marlowe short story for 20 years. As yet [March 1959] unpublished.”
        Gift of Raymond Chandler, March 1959.
      - Sonnet 13. n.p., Spring 1958; (2 items: 1 leaf [1p.] and 1 copy - typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Bang to Rights. London., 1958; (1 leaf, holograph, written in red ink). (Box 8, Folder 4)
        Foreword to the book by Frank Norman. Bang to Rights was published by Secker & Warburg, London, 1958.
        Gift of Mrs. Helga Greene, June 1959.
      - Poodle Springs Story. La Jolla., 1959; (2 items: 23 leaves, 2 leaves - typescript with holograph corrections and 2 leaves, blue paper). (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Chandler's last novel, unfinished at the time of his death in 1959. With detailed description of the house in the novel.
      - Farewell, My Lovely. Hollywood., June 7, 1944; (1 leaf, mimeograph). (Box 9, Folder 2)
        Synopsis.
      - Playback., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
        Gift of Edgar N. Carter, H.N. Swanson, Incorporated, December 1959.
        - “Story idea.” Hollywood., circa 1947; (5 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections). (Box 9, Folder 6)
          With Chandler's note: “Swanie: I think it stinks. Ray.”
        - Story idea. Hollywood., circa 1947; (9 leaves, typescript carbon). (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Publications. v.p., 1911-1963 (Box 2-5, 7-8, 12-14)
      - The Clay God. n.p., 1911[?]; (1p., clipping). (Box 2, Folder 32)
        With penciled note on verso, “either Westiminster Gazette or Academy, c. 1911?”
      - The Fairy King. n.p., 1911[?]; (1p., clipping). (Box 2, Folder 33)
        With pencilled note on verso, “either Westminster Gazette or Academy, c. 1911.”
      - A Pilgrim in Meditation. n.p., 1911[?]; (1p., clipping). (Box 2, Folder 35)
        With pencilled note on verso “either Westminster Gazette or Academy c. 1911.”
      - Blackmailer's Don't Shoot., December 1933; (pp.8-35, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 36)
        Black Mask (vol.26, no.10).
      - Smart-Aleck Kill., July 1934; (pp.54-78, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 37)
        Black Mask (vol.17, no.8).
      - Finger Man., October 1934; (pp.8-39, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Killer in the Rain., January 1935; (pp.3-23, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 39)
        Black Mask (vol.17, no.11).
      - Nevada Gas., June 1935; (pp.8-35, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 40)
        Black Mask (vol.18, no.4).
        Black cover stamped “W.W. Martindale, Third & Broadway, Santa Monica, Calif.”
      - Spanish Blood., November 1935; (pp.38-64, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 41)
        Black Mask (vol.18, no.9).
      - Guns at Cyrano's., January 1936; (pp.8-37, original issue). (Box 2, Folder 42)
        Black Mask (vol.18, no.11).
      - The Man Who Liked Dogs., March 1936; (pp.10-33, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Black Mask (vol.19, no.1).
        Stamped on back cover “Grand Central Market.”
      - Noon Street Nemesis., May 30, 1936; (pp.36-62, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 2)
        Detective Fiction Weekly (vol.52, no.4).
        With Raymond Chandler's corrections in pencil throughout.
        Title has been crossed out and replaced with “Pick-up on Noon Street.” Stamped on back cover, “Grand Central Market.”
      - Goldfish., September 1936; (pp.10-35, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Black Mask (vol.19, no.7).
      - The Curtain., September 1936; (pp.10-33, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Try the Girl., January 1937; (pp.10-34, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 5)
        Black Mask (vol.19, no.11).
      - Mandarin's Jade., November 1937; (pp.36-67, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 6)
        Dime Detective (vol.25, no.4).
        Stamped on back cover, “W.W. Martindale, Oct. 13, 1937, Santa Monica, Calif.”
      - Red Wind., January 1938; (pp.40-70, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Dime Detective (vol.26, no.2).
        Stamped on back cover, “Grand Central Market, 1328 -4th Street, Santa Monica, Calif.”
      - The King in Yellow., March 1938; (pp.42-74, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 8)
        Dime Detective (vol.26, no.4).
      - Bay city blues., June 1938; (pp.6-47, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 9)
        Dime Detective (vol.27, no.3).
      - The Big Sleep - Publication announcement., December 24, 1938; (Original issue). (Box 3, Folder 10)
        Cover story in Publisher's Weekly (vol.84, no.26).
        re publication of The Big Sleep in February 1939.
      - The Lady in the Lake., January 1939; (pp.94, 127, original issue). (Box 3, Folder 11)
        Dime Detective (vol.29, no.2).
      - Trouble is My Business., August 1939; (pp.42-76, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Dime Detective (vol.31, no.1).
      - No Crime in the Mountains., September 1941; (pp.9-54, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Street & Smith's Detective Story Magazine (vol.67, no.5).
      - New editions of Chandler novels., circa 1945[?]; (Original issue). (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Bulletin in Atlantic Monthly (vol.173, no.1).
        Notice re 25 cent editions of The Big Sleep, Farewell, My Lovely, The Lady in the Lake, and The High Window.
      - The Chandler books [by] D.C. Russell., March 1945; (2 items: pp.123, 124 and galleys, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Atlantic Monthly (vol.173, no.3).
      - Writers in Hollywood., November 1945; (pp.50-54, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Atlantic Monthly (vol.176, no.5).
      - The Hollywood Bowl., January 1947; (pp.108-109, clipping). (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Atlantic Monthly (vol.179, no.1).
      - Oscar Night in Hollywood., March 1948; (pp.24-27, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Atlantic Monthly (vol.181, no.4).
      - Studies in Extinction., October 1948; (pp.50-55, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 9)
        Raymond Candler's file copy.
      - Ten Greatest Crimes., October 1948; (pp.50-53, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 10)
        Cosmopolitan (vol.125, no.4).
      - The Little Sister., April 1949; (pp.173, 196, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Cosmopolitan (vol.26, no.4).
      - The Simple Art of Murder., 1950 April 15; (pp.13-14, original issue, marked in red ink). (Box 4, Folder 15)
        Saturday Review (vol.33, no.15).
        With Raymond Chandler's addresss label on the cover, “6005 Camino de la Costa, La Jolla, Calif.”
        With a clipping of the same article.
      - Oscar Night in Hollywood., June 1950; (pp.157, 161, original issue, marked in red ink). (Box 4, Folder 16)
        Sight and Sound (vol.19, no.4).
      - The Hollywood Ten., Spring 1951; (pp.93-94, original issue). (Box 4, Folder 17)
        The Author (vol.61, no.3).
        With Raymond Chandler's address stamp on the cover.
      - Professor Bingo's Snuff (Published). London., June / July 1951; (pp.81-93, clipping). (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Go.
      - Ten Percent of Your Life., February 1953; (pp.48-51, original issue). (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Atlantic Monthly (vol.189, no.2).
        Marked in Raymond Chandler's hand, “File copy.” Stamped with Raymond Chandler's La Jolla address.
      - Black Mask [by] Frank Boreman., February/March 1952; (pp.63-65, original issue). (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Go, no.6 (new series).
        With photostatic copy of the article.
      - Professor Bingo's Snuff., Summer 1952; (pp.119, 160, original issue). (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Fantastic (vol.1, no.1).
        Raymond Chandler file copy[?].
      - Requiem - Fair copy. n.p., n.d.; (2 leaves [2pp.], typescript carbon with holograph note by Dorothy Gardiner). (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Typed note at the top: “Get permission from Atlantic Monthly, 1957.”
        DG's note: “This poem, written in January 1955 was accepted and paid for by the Atlantic Monthly, but never published.
        DG Price $35.00.”
        Cataloging note: “from James Sandoe folder.”
      - “Cops” by Raymond Chandler. In Crosstown With Neil Morgan. San Diego., August 25, 1959; (2 items, 2 leaves, proofs). (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
        2 parts, published posthumously.
      - Bonded Goods. n.p., circa 1956; (2 items: 1 leaf, 1 leaf, clippings). (Box 5, Folder 15)
        Book review. Review of Ian Fleming's Diamonds Are Forever.
      - Playback., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
        - Clipping in Bookseller (vol.[ ], no.[ ])., March 1958; (p.1123). (Box 7, Folder 4)
          Hamish Hamilton advertisement re publication of Playback in July 1958.
        - Galleys for the American edition. n.p., May 16, 1958; (79 sheets). (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Author's proof for the American edition. n.p., August 7, 1958; (71 sheets). (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - The Poodle Springs Story - Research material. Cathedral City., circa 1958; (1 leaf [2pp.], publication). (Box 8, Folder 5)
        Map showing points of interest around Cathedral City. With note and markings by Raymond Chandler.
      - Wrong Pidgeon., February 1960; (pp.1-28, original issue). (Box 8, Folder 8)
        Manhunt (vol.8, no.1).
      - I'll Be Waiting., October 14, 1939; (pp.10, 11, 72, 74, 78, clipping). (Box 14, Folder 1)
        Saturday Evening Post (vol.[ ], no.[ ]). Illustrated by Hy Rubin.
      - Marlowe Takes on the Syndicate. London., April 6-9, 1959; (4 items: 5 pp., clippings). (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Daily Mail. Original title was “The pencil.”
      - Killer in the Rain edited by Philip Durham. v.p., v.d. (Box 12-13)
        - Research material. v.p., v.d.; (27 items). (Box 12, Folder 27)
          Various, clippings, notes, maps.
        - “Blackmailers Don't Shoot.” n.p., October 13, 1960; (2 items: 79 leaves, 1 leaf - typescript(carbon), holograph). (Box 13, Folder 1)
          Not used in Killer in the Rain.
          With holograph note from Helga Greene. “'Blackmailers don't shoot' not used in this edition.”
        - Corrected page proofs with holograph corrections. London., circa 1963; (332pp.). (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Introduction. Los Angeles., circa 1963; (12 leaves, holograph). (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Passed proofs with holograph corrections. London., 1963 December 14 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Copies of “The Curtain,” “Killer in the Rain,” “The Man Who Liked Dogs,” “Try the Girl.”. n.p., n.d.; 4 items: 49, 55, 48, 52 leaves - typescript carbon). (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Copies of “Mandarin Jade,” “Bay City Blues,” “Lady in the Lake,” “No Crime in the Mountains.” n.p., 4 items: 73, 88, 68 and 81 leaves - typescript carbon). (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Screenwriting and Adaptations of Chandler Novels
    - And Now Tomorrow. By Raymond Chandler and Frank Partos - Screenplay. Hollywood., December 3, 1943; (128 leaves, mimeograph, bound in quarter morocco leather). (Box 8, Folder 9)
      With 10 stills from the Paramount production.
      Gift of Irving Pichel, director of the film, 1960.
    - Double Indemnity By Raymond Chandler and Billy Wilder - Screenplay. Hollywood., 1943-1944 (Box 8-9)
      - Test scene by Raymond Chandler and Billy Wilder., (20 leaves). (Box 8, Folder 10)
        Photocopy of material in Box 8, folder 11.
      - Test scene by Raymond Chandler and Billy Wilder., (20 leaves, holograph with extensive corrections). (Box 8, Folder 11)
        Clipped with this are addresses of Wilder and Joe Sistrom, the producer.
        Gift of Paramount Studios, n.d.
        NO PHOTOCOPYING
      - “Billy Wilder's personal marked copy.” Hollywood., September 25, 1943; (pp.1-52 of 111 [132 leaves] - typescript and mimeograph, Blue wrappers). (Box 8, Folder 12)
        With corrections and notes by Wilder.
        Purchase[?].
      - “Billy Wilder's personal marked copy.” Hollywood., September 25, 1943; (pp.53-111 of 111 [132 leaves] - typescript and mimeograph, Blue wrappers). (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Complete script with cast of characters. #2915. Hollywood., September 25, 1943; (117 leaves, mimeograph, Unbound). (Box 9, Folder 1)
        Gift of Billy Wilder, 1961.
    - Double Indemnity - Post production material. Hollywood., March 15, 1945; (8pp. program). (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Nomination for Best Written Screenplay [Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences program].
    - Backfire - Story for the screen. Los Angeles., 1946; (1 p.l., 8 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Manuscript.
      Gift of Edgar N. Carter of, H.N. Swanson, Incorporated, December 1959.
    - The Big Sleep - Production material. Hollywood., 1946; (3 items: 1 leaf, 2 leaves, 3 leaves, mimeograph). (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Cast and credits, synopsis, production notes. Cast and credits, August 21, 1946. Synopsis, January 29, 1946. Production notes, February 20, 1946.
    - The Blue Dahlia - Post production material. Hollywood., 1946 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - List of eligible releases for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences writing awards. Hollywood., 1946; (16pp., brochure). (Box 12, Folder 13)
        Films eligible for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences writing awards for 1946.
      - Program for awards ceremony. Los Angeles., March 13, 1947; (8pp.). (Box 12, Folder 13)
        Nomination for Best Original Screenplay for 1946. Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences awards program.
    - The Lady in the Lake - Production material. Culver City., 1946; (3 items: 1 leaf, 1 leaf, 1 leaf, mimeograph). (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Press release, press release, cast and crew. Press release, March 28, 1946. Press release May 29, 1946. Cast and crew, November 21, 1946.
    - Playback - Screenplay. Universal City., September 30, 1947; (224pp., typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 9, Folder 8)
      First draft continuity.
    - Strangers on a Train - Screenplay. n.p., 1950 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
      - Treatment by Cook Whitfield. n.p., June 20, 1950; (65pp., typescript carbon with pencil notations). (Box 9, Folder 9)
        Purchase.
      - Revised treatment (1st). n.p., July 18-19, 1950; (41pp., typescript). (Box 9, Folder 10)
        “Alfred Hitchcock copy.”
      - Revised treatment. La Jolla., July 28, 1950; (108pp., typescript carbon). (Box 9, Folder 11)
        With Chandler's address stamped on the last page.
    - Backfire - Story for the screen. Santa Barbara., 1984 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
      - Publication. Santa Barbara., 1984; (3 items). (Box 13, Folder 7)
        Print samples, hardbound, paperback, and unbound signatures.
        Gift of James Pepper, 1984[?].
      - Publication material. Santa Barbara., circa 1984; (17 items, print and photocopy). (Box 13, Folder 8)
        Cover design samples.
        With notes by James Pepper, publisher.
  - BBC Production
    - The Long Good-bye; The Critics - Manuscript. London., 1953[?]; (2 items: 5 leaves, 1 leaf - mimeograph). (Box 12, Folder 14)
      Commentary by Malcolm Muggeridge. With “compliments” card from Helga Greene.
- Writings By and About Raymond Chandler
  - Published
    - Raymond Chandler speaking. v.p., 1959 (Box 9-12)
      - Correspondence. New York., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Letters between Dorothy Gardiner and James Sandoe., (3 items: 1 leaf, 2 leaves, 2 leaves - 2 typescripts signed and typescript carbon). (Box 9, Folder 12)
          Letter from Dorothy Gardiner to James Sandoe and Sandoe's undated reply. With 2pp. of a bibliography of Frederick Anderson.
      - Manuscripts. n.p. and New York., 1960 (Box 10-12)
        - Letters from Dorothy Gardiner to Paul Brooks and outlines., September 14, 1960; (2 items: 4 and 36 leaves, typescript). (Box 10, Folder 1)
          Also, 36pp. of text.
        - pp.1-224. n.p., n.d.; (Typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - pp.225-399. n.p., n.d.; (Typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - pp.400-543. n.p., n.d.; (Typescript and typescript carbon). (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (65 items: ca. 80 leaves, typecript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 10, Folder 5)
          Folder 1 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (140 items: ca. 170 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 10, Folder 6)
          Folder 2 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (145 items: ca. 180 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 10, Folder 7)
          Folder 3 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (140 items: ca. 180 leaves, typescript, typescript carbon and photostatic copies).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 1)
          Folder 4 of 8.
        - Copies of Raymond Chandler letters. n.p., (60 items: ca. 70 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon).; Item count approximate.. (Box 11, Folder 2)